<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>TurtleShroom Productions Proudly Presents: CKAPP Tropical Rainforest Mod (Continued)</name>
  <packageId>Mlie.TropickappRainforestMod</packageId>
  <author>Kaptain Kaverns, Mlie, TurtleShroom</author>
  <url>https://github.com/emipa606/TropickappRainforestMod</url>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.0</li>
    <li>1.1</li>
    <li>1.2</li>
    <li>1.3</li>
    <li>1.4</li>
    <li>1.5</li>
	<li>1.6</li>
  </supportedVersions>
	<modDependenciesByVersion>
		<v1.0></v1.0>
		<v1.1></v1.1>
		<v1.2></v1.2>
		<v1.3></v1.3>
		<v1.4></v1.4>
		<v1.5></v1.5>
		<v1.6>
		  <li>
			<packageId>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</packageId>
			<displayName>Vanilla Factions Expanded Framework Mod</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>https://www.steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2023507013</steamWorkshopUrl>
		  </li>
		</v1.6>
	</modDependenciesByVersion>
  <loadAfter>
    <li>spoonshortage.ADogSaidAnimalProsthetics</li>
	<li>sambucher.adogsaidanimalprosthetics2</li>
    <li>yanzihko.ffr</li>
    <li>yanzihko.yzrcm</li>
    <li>vanillaexpanded.vanillaanimalsexpanded</li>
    <li>vanillaexpanded.vaeroy</li>
    <li>BiomesTeam.BiomesCore</li>
    <li>syrchalis.universalfermenter</li>
    <li>syrchalis.processor.framework</li>
    <li>erdelf.HumanoidAlienRaces</li>
    <li>OskarPotocki.VanillaFactionsExpanded.Core</li>
    <li>dajian.chiteaditional.expanded</li>
    <li>chiexpanded.english</li>
    <li>heis.edo.themed.expansion</li>
    <li>trickity.samurai.faction</li>
    <li>heis.edo.themed.expansion.redundancy.patch</li>
	<li>vanillaexpanded.vplantse</li>
	<li>vanillaexpanded.vaeroy</li>
	<li>vanillaexpanded.vaeroy.omegachickenpatch</li>
	<li>hc.animal.continued</li>
	<li>vanillaexpanded.vplantsemore</li>
	<li>vanillaexpanded.vplantsemushrooms</li>
  </loadAfter>
  <loadBefore>
    <li>tsp.isengriff.storytime</li>
    <li>ender.snaketophat</li>
	<li>tsp.beelievers</li>
	<li>zal.patchhoney</li>
	<li>tsp.zal.patchhoney2</li>
	<li>tsp.velcroboy333.medievalfestival.banquet</li>
	<li>tsp.girlbominations</li>
  </loadBefore>
  <description>[H1]TurtleShroom Productions Proudly Presents: CKAPP Tropical Rainforest Mod (Continued)[/H1]
  
  Thank you for downloading the continuation of the CKAPP Tropical Rainforest Mod. It is my privilege to, with Mlie's encouragement, take another load off his shoulders and continue the ambitious project of bringing one of "Rimworld's" best Biome balance changing Mods back to the RW Steam Workshop. This Mod causes the Tropical Rainforest (and many other tropical Biomes) to be dense in vegetation and teeming with animal life. It greatly increases the amount and types of animals.
  
  With "Odyssey" support, duplicated creatures are resolved (so, for example, tigers in this Mod are directly related to "Odyssey" Tigers) and adjusted to minimize both bloat and conflicts. The exotic forms of weather in "Odyssey" are also factored in, leading to realistic monsoons and flooding. In all, this Mod makes tropical climates more challenging and fun to play,as well as giving players a wealth of abundant resources to employ in their colonial endeavors.
  
  This version fixes many, MANY bugs from the Mlie version, many of which I accidentally created myself. I give out special thanks to the user Bernau31 and his diligence in documenting the exact erorrs, down to the very Thing Defs and names of those involved! That was invaluable!
  
  FUTURE PLANS:
	1. Support for the Vanilla Factions Expanded Medieval Mod's Draught system (Dream Roots, Jitter Berries, etc.)
	2. Support for the Medieval Overhaul Mod's Alchemy system (Dream Roots, Jitter Berries, etc.)
	3. Further "Odyssey" integration, possible combining of Pawn Kind Defs and Thing Defs for duplicated animals
  
  
  
____________________________________

[U][B]ORIGINAL DESCRIPTION[/B][/U]

Update of KapTaiN_KaVerNs mod
https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1110093272

Removed the need for ModCheck and Harmony by using vanilla-patching.	
Initial loading of a new map may take a while due to the large amount of plants that need to spawn.

Added patches for:
[list]
[*] [url=https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=2312280343][RF] Archipelagos (Continued)[/url]
[*] [url=https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=2038001322]Biomes! Islands[/url]
[*] [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2871933948]Vanilla Factions Animals Expanded[/url] 
[*] [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2858079457]Vanilla Factions Animals Expanded (Royal)[/url]
[*] [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2690125435]Feles of the Rim[/url]
[/list]


The purpose of this mod is to add a significant amount of new animals and plants to the Tropical Rainforest and Tropical Swamp Biome and increase their fauna and flora diversity.


[h1]Description[/h1]
The new tropical biomes are challenging biomes with deadly diseases, strong animals, intense rainstorms and a thick jungle canopy that makes movement and expansion a challenge.

[b]Added Animals :[/b]

Jaguar, Panda Bear, Tiger, White Tiger, Tapir, Junglefowl, Peafowl, Okapi

[b]Added Plants :[/b]

Ferns, Palm Tree, Mahogany Tree, Strangler Fig, Bromeliad, Wild Rice, Bamboo, Taro, Stump Tree, Banana, Lemongrass, Coconut Palm, DreamVine, Heliconia, Jitter-Weed, Wild Smokeleaf, Wild Psychoid, Wild Cotton, Rafflesia, Hive in a tree

[b]Added Consumables :[/b]

Taro Root, Coconuts, Bananas, Jitter Berries (drug), Lemongrass, Dream Root (drug and can be used to craft Neutroamine), Honeycomb

[h1]Some tips for surviving the rain forest:[/h1]

   - Clear out plants for pathing. The dense jungle will considerably slow down pawns.
   - Wood is abundant, but trees take a long time to chop down. Prioritize time and resources and focus on smaller trees and plants when clearing large areas.
   - Foraging is a viable food option. Look out for rice, bananas, coconuts and lemongrass.
   - While rare, jitter berries, smokeleaf, psycoid, healroot and cotton can also be foraged.
   - The rain forest provides a lot of cover. Clear out areas to hit enemies, or use the cover to your advantage.
   - Some animals in the rain forest do a lot of damage and are very fast. Choose fights wisely and try to avoid being ambushed.
   - The rain forest rains a lot, so consider this when deciding on power and building options.
   - Remove rafflesias from your area as these drastically reduce beauty.
   - You can stop plant movement sway in the vanilla options menu.

[h1]Compatibility[/h1]

- A Dog Said ... compatibility patch is now integrated. Be sure to put this mod AFTER [b]A Dog Said...[/b]

____________________________________
[h1]All animals and plants were designed by Coercion[/h1]
[h1]Pith helmet was designed by Thirite[/h1]


[list]
[*] See if the the error persists if you just have this mod and its requirements active.
[*] If not, try adding your other mods until it happens again.
[*] Post your error-log using [url=https://steamcommunity.com/workshop/filedetails/?id=818773962]HugsLib[/url] or the standalone [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2873415404]Uploader[/url] and command Ctrl+F12
[*] For best support, please use the Discord-channel for error-reporting.
[*] Do not report errors by making a discussion-thread, I get no notification of that.
[*] If you have the solution for a problem, please post it to the GitHub repository.
[*] Use [url=https://github.com/RimSort/RimSort/releases/latest]RimSort[/url] to sort your mods
[/list]

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/changelog/2028973691]Change Log[/url]</description>
  <modVersion IgnoreIfNoMatchingField="True">1.5.2</modVersion>
</ModMetaData>